Guide to the Theatre recordings collection, 1960s
George Mason University Libraries
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
Theatre recordings collection
1960s
George Mason University. Special Collections and Archives.
George Mason University. School of Theater
C0170
1 linear feet (2 boxes)
14 LP record albums of cast recordings. Some albums include pamphlets with descriptions of the plays as well as the text from the scripts. Many were created by the Theatre Recording Society and Columbia Records.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donated by the George Mason University Theatre Department in 2009.
Historical Information
Theatre recordings became popular in the 1950s with the introduction of Long Playing (LP) records. This format allowed for longer musical compositions such as classical music and Broadway recordings. Columbia was one of the first record companies to sell LPs that featured the original cast recordings.
Scope and Content
14 LP record albums of cast recordings. Some albums include pamphlets with descriptions of the plays as well as the text from the scripts. Many were created by the Theatre Recording Society and Columbia Records.
Arrangement
Organized by title.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Special Collections and Archives also holds many other theatre collections.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Theater--New York (State)--New York.
Document Types:
Live sound recordings.
Contents List
- Series 1: Live Theatre Recordings, 1960s
  14 LP record albums of cast recordings.
  - Madea, 1960s (Box 1-2)
    Written by: Euripides Directed by: Howard Sackler
  - Cyrano de Bergerac, 1960s (Box 1-2)
    Written by: Edmond Rostand
  - The Old Glory Benito Cerano, 1960s (Box 1-2)
    Written by: Robert Lowell
  - MARAT/SADE, 1960s (Box 1-2)
    Written by: Peter Weiss; Royal Shakespeare Company
  - Who's Afraid of Virginia Woolf, 1960s (Box 1-2)
    Written by: Edward Albee; Original Broadway Cast
  - Arthur Miller's After the Fall, 1960s (Box 1-2)
    The Reparatory Theater of Lincoln Center; Original Cast Recording
  - The Hostage, 1960s (Box 1-2)
    Written by: Brendan Behan; Starring Julie Harris and Geoff Garland
  - MACBIRD, 1960s (Box 1-2)
    Written by: Barbara Garson; Original Cast Recording
  - Uncle Vanya, 1960s (Box 1-2)
    Written by: Anton Chekhov; Chichester Festival Theatre; The Production by Lawrence Olivier
  - The Balcony, 1960s (Box 1-2)
    Written by: Jean Genet
  - Cesar and Cleopatra, 1960s (Box 1-2)
    Written by: Bernard Shaw; Directed by Anthony Quayle
  - King Richard III, 1960s (Box 1-2)
    Written by: William Shakespeare; Directed by: Howard Sackler
  - The Glass Menagerie, 1960s (Box 1-2)
    Written by: Tennessee Williams; Directed by: Howard Sackler
  - Death of a Salesman, 1960s (Box 1-2)
    Written by: Arthur Miller; Directed by: Ulu Grosbard; Starring Lee J. Cobb and Mildred Dunnock